Guide to the Rockefeller's business records, 1978-2016 MS 655
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rockefeller's business records
1978-2016, bulk dates 1978-1995
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rockefeller's
MS 655
3 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
This collection consists of the business records, promotional calendars, and digital images that chronicle Rockefeller's music venue.
Biographical / Historical
The music venue, Rockefeller's, began as way to cover the renovation costs of the historic Citizens/Heights State Bank building on 3620 Washington Avenue in Houston. In the beginning, Sanford and Susan Criner envisioned a performance space for local talent. Early on, they realized that local acts were not enough to fill the hall. The Criners turned to booking jazz acts and made a trip to Los Angeles to promote the venue to bigger names. The trip was incredibly successful.
From 1979 to 1997, Rockefeller's hosted great performers from a variety of genres: blues, jazz, rock, country, and comedy. Count Basie, Dizzy Gillespie, Ella Fitzgerald, James Brown, John Lee Hooker, Ray Charles, Jerry Lee Lewis, Carl Perkins, Fats Domino, Merle Haggard, Waylon Jennings, Chet Atkins, Garth Brooks, Bonnie Raitt, the Dixie Chicks, Pee-wee Herman, Bill Hicks, and Timothy Leary all graced the stage. While ownership of Rockefeller's changed hands during that time, the venue always thrived on presenting Houston with a wide mix of talent.
As for the renovation, Taft Architects and construction manager Matt Pasternak headed up the project. The revitalized building, originally designed by Joseph Finger, won a Texas Society of Architects Honor Award for historical preservation.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the business records, including artist booking sheets and contracts, as well as promotional calendars, news clippings, and digital images that chronicle the history of the Houston music venue Rockefeller's.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Accruals
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Sanford and Susan Criner in 2016.
Related Materials
Please see the Rice University KTRU Radio records, UA 011.
Index Terms
Subjects
African Americans; Music; Blues (Music); Rock music; Rock concerts; Folk music; Folk-rock music; Jazz; Rhythm and blues music; Stand-up comedy; Business; Women
Subjects (Persons)
Criner, Sanford; Criner, Susan
Subjects (Corporations)
Rockefeller's
- Series I: Business Files
  - Booking records, 1979-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1994-11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1994-12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1995-01 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1995-02 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1995-03 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1995-04 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1995-05 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1995-06 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1995-07 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1995-09 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Booking sheets and performance contracts, 1995-10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Corporate bookings, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cost analysis, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Expenses, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Press releases and promotions, 1982-1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Promotions portfolio, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Renovation, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Schedules, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Schedules, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Seating chart, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Ticket sales ledger, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ticket sales ledger, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ticket sales ledger, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ticket sales ledger, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Ticket sales ledger and ticket, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Twenty-Five Years of Rockefeller's", 1994 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Venue promotion, 1979-1990s (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Series II: News Clippings
  - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - 1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 2016 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series III: Promotional Calendars
  - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 1997 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series IV: Photographs
  - Photographs, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Series V: Posters
  - The Neville Brothers (1 yellow and 1 orange), 1985-06-22 (Box 3)
  - Poco (1 green and 1 yellow), 1985-08-02 (Box 3)
  - Doctor John, 1985-09-20 - 1985-09-21 (Box 3)
  - Randy Newman, 1985-10-27 (Box 3)
  - Loudon Wainwright III with The Banded Geckos, 1986-01-30 (Box 3)
  - Roomful of Blues, 1986-02-06 - 1986-02-07 (Box 3)
  - Mitch Ryder with David Wayne Kleb, 1986-03-17 (Box 3)
  - Warren Zevon with Bill Hicks, 1986-06-18 (Box 3)
  - War, 1986-06-28 (Box 3)
  - Wynton Marsalis, 1986-07-04 - 1986-07-05 (Box 3)
  - Nicolete Larson, 1986-08-01 (Box 3)
  - The Neville Brothers, 1986-08-31 (Box 3)
  - Sandra Bernhard, 1986-09-07 (Box 3)
  - Little Bobby Duncan's Rock and Roll Coloring Book, 1985 (Box 3)